NAVEEN VINTA

Washington D.C Metro

(312) 622-2648 linkedin.com/in/nvinta naveen.vinta@icloud.com

TRANSFORMATIVE TECHNOLOGY LEADER

DRIVING STRATEGIC DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION WITH INCLUSIVITY

As an IT leader with experience in Cybersecurity, Solution Architecture, and Cloud Computing and a US Army veteran, I am pursuing an Executive MBA to further develop my business acumen and pivot to operator roles in private equity. Led high-performing teams managing budgets of \$50M+; I excel at delivering exceptional results and maximizing impact for the mission and team. My adaptable leadership style ensures strategic alignment with organizational goals, making me well-suited to drive business transformation and create value for private equity firms.

- Technical Strategy
- Cybersecurity Policy
- Program Management

- Client Relations
- Team Building and Mentoring
- Managed 50M + P&L

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

THE ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY, Washington, D.C Information Management Officer

2023-Present

- Advised Senior Information Officer (SIO) and high-level executives, providing guidance on technology innovation and implementing digital transformation initiatives within the Office of Water (OW).
- Liaised between IT professionals and technical program experts, as a technology SME.
- Led strategic initiatives to improve IT operations and programs, resulting in a 30% increase in operational efficiency and 15% reduction in costs.
- Managed risks to IT system and data by identifying, assessing, and mitigating potential risks, resulting in appropriate risk management and reduced overall risk.
- Monitor emerging trends and recommend improvements to increase efficiency and reduce release time by up to 50%.

CGI, Fairfax, VA 2020-2023

Director Consulting Services

- Executed a cloud-first strategy, resulting in revenue increase of 25% and 20% improvement in P&L.
- Managed program with three task orders totaling \$50M, overseeing a team of 30 resources and delivering 95% of projects on-time and under budget.
- Enhanced client relations by delivering actionable insights and recommendations for digital transformation, resulting in 30% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Expanded portfolio by identifying opportunities and leveraging capabilities, resulting in a 15% increase in year-over-year growth.
- Improved recruitment, retention, and member satisfaction, providing coaching and mentorship resulting in a 40% increase in internal promotions.
- Led the effort to successfully win the recompete of a cybersecurity contract with a 40% increased total contract value.

U.S DEPARTMENT OF STATE, Washington, D.C.

2016-2020

Information System Security Officer & Project Manager

- Led Certification and Accreditation of FISMA High-Value Asset, achieving compliance with federal regulations and standards.
- Reviewed and evaluated customer responsibility matrix for FedRamp-certified Cloud Service Providers (SalesForce, ServiceNow, Microsoft Azure, Oracle Fusion Cloud), improving compliance and security.

- Managed a team of 20 resources modernizing applications into Service Oriented Architecture improving interoperability and ease of maintenance.
- Improved customer service for HR IT functions, resulting in increased satisfaction and streamlined processes.

U.S DEPARTMENT OF LABOR, Washington, D.C.

2015-2016

IT Specialist

- Oversaw contractor work as IT Specialist for Office of Information Systems and Technology (OIST) in Employment and Training Administration, ensuring successful project delivery.
- Procured department-wide IDaaS solution, improving security and streamlining access management across the organization.

BANKERS LIFE, Chicago, IL

2013-2015

Sr. Lead Application Developer

- Designed Spring MVC portal application with single sign-on for 6,000 agents, 400 corporate users, and 50 support technicians, enabling access to compensation statements, training, policies, history, and applications.
- Created Use Case, sequence, activity, state, architecture, and deployment diagrams, conducting fit-gap analysis to address stakeholder requirements.
- Presented to senior leadership on the application, and provided training to end users.

US ARMY, Ft. Bliss, TX

2010-2013

Specialist

• M1A1 Abrams Tank Mechanic

FORD MOTOR COMPANY, Dearborn, MI

2007-2010

Sr. Developer

- Designed new online BOM process to assist Material Departments with early BOM process for future vehicle programs, replacing existing bulky process.
- Contributed to Ford's Blue Oval Certification, streamlining personnel certification process for dealer employees resulting in a 15% increased year-over-year sales.
- Led the effort to integrate IT modules with TATA resulting from an acquisition.

NORTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY, Fargo, ND

2005-2007

Research Assistance

Worked as a research assistant in the Electrical and Computer Engineering.

- Designed sensor network with RFID capability and GPS for food transportation, used by multiple departments throughout campus.
- Developed Java components to interpret data in engineering units from three devices and export results to MySQL.
- Created GUI to monitor network trace and communication between nodes.

EDUCATION

University of Virginia Darden School of Business, Rosslyn, VA

Executive MBA Candidate April, 2024

George Mason University, Fairfax, VA

Master of Science in Technology Management May, 2020

North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND

Master of Software Engineering

August, 2017